<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ipod touch on Reflections</title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/ipod-touch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ipod touch on Reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2016 &amp;copy; Shivanand Velmurugan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.shiv.me/tags/ipod-touch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>That queasy feeling</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/01/29/that-queasy-feeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/01/29/that-queasy-feeling/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, I returned the Ipod touch that I had for exactly 11 days, coz Apple chose to charge me $20. Apart from me being a cheap bas***d, I had this queasy feeling in my gut, about apple products. I felt an unexplainable rage towards Apple, Jobs and the fanboys. I am usually a very moderate person, and it really surprised me that I could harbor such crazy extremism and frustration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bye bye IPOD</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/01/18/bye-bye-ipod/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/01/18/bye-bye-ipod/</guid>
      <description>Since I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoyed being screwed over when I buy a $500 product, I said buh-bye to my ipod touch today. One thing that I enjoyed, was the sharpness of the display. I will definetly buy this device again, if I knew for sure that, Apple will not pull another stunt like that with the imminent release of IPOD touch SDK. So until then, I commute for 2 hours everyday with no music to listen, no podcast from CNN to watch :(</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPOD touch: Downgrade from 1.1.3 to 1.1.1</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/01/16/ipod-touch-downgrade-from-1.1.3-to-1.1.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/01/16/ipod-touch-downgrade-from-1.1.3-to-1.1.1/</guid>
      <description>My ipod touch was upgraded to 1.1.3, after connecting to my computer, and I wanted to downgrade to 1.1.1, so I could jailbreak it and put any app I want on it.
ipodtouchmaster found a way to downgrade it using iPhuc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPod touch 1.1.1 firmware link</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/01/15/ipod-touch-1.1.1-firmware-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/01/15/ipod-touch-1.1.1-firmware-link/</guid>
      <description>Since Apple&amp;rsquo;s is so bent upon disappointing their customers, by introducing paid firmware upgrades, I needed to ensure that I have the option to jail break, my new ipod touch (if need be). (update: the firmware upgrade itself is not paid. Only the newapps are paid). I am going to wait until they release their SDK in February before I jailbreak mine.
I found a link to the 1.1.1 firmware (thanks to Rupert and who-ever posted this).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ipod touch/Iphone support</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/01/15/ipod-touch/iphone-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/01/15/ipod-touch/iphone-support/</guid>
      <description>This website, now supports a special interface for viewing usingÂ ipod touch/iphone. I&amp;rsquo;m using the iWPhone plugin at contentrobot.com</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
