<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prawns on shiv.me</title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/prawns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prawns on shiv.me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2016 &amp;copy; Shivanand Velmurugan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.shiv.me/tags/prawns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Prawn curry</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/12/14/prawn-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/12/14/prawn-curry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are in a hurry, and need something tasty yet easy to make, this one is for you. The prep time is about 5 minutes, and the cooking time around 10-15 minutes. If you have a small rice cooker &amp;ndash; the kind that plugs into a wall sockets &amp;ndash; you should be able to get the rice done in about the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also the perfect curry to cook for smaller portions. If you are like me, and have to cook for 1 person, aka me,  all the time, it is a no-frills and no-freezer required recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Fry all the onions until soft (5-6 mins) in high heat&lt;br /&gt;
2. add mined garlic, 1 tsp jeera, 1 tsp dania powder, and salt to taste, some tumeric powder (1 tsp for each handful of prawns), and chilli powder to taste (I use very little)&lt;br /&gt;
3. add some salt (increases the temp and allows everything to sear nicely)&lt;br /&gt;
4. cook for 4 mins or until the prawns are half-cooked&lt;br /&gt;
5. add diced tomatoes, and salt to taste (remember to taste the sauce before adding the salt)&lt;br /&gt;
6. sear for 1 min and then add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of water (not too much or you will over cook the prawns), and reduce heat, and simmer until the above consistency is reached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cook some rice, and you have a decent meal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some pictures:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gallery link=&amp;ldquo;file&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>