<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shiv.me </title>
    <link>/tags/gs-maheswari/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2008-05-25 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>So long and thanks for all the good times</title>
          <link>/2008/05/so-long-and-thanks-for-all-the-good-times/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
          <guid>/2008/05/so-long-and-thanks-for-all-the-good-times/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been away from the internet for most of the last week. There are only a few things that can keep me away from spending hours reading feeds or uploading pictures, and when those things do happen, it is not very pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I lost yet another wonderful person from my life. I lost my father-in-law, Mr. Ghanshyam Maheswari. He was a good man, a good soul, a great father, and most of all, someone who lived his life - truly lived every moment of it. I can&amp;rsquo;t find words to express the loss I feel. As the hours on the plane ride half way across the world passed, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t begin to accept that he had really passed on. I guess, a part of me was expecting to see him at the airport, telling my wife and me that this was all just a dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life, and not death, is cruel. It makes us experience a lot of things that we could do without. With the greatest regret and effort, I need to muster the ability to bid adieu, to a wonderful person that has enriched the lives of several who have been left behind. Mr Maheswari, may you find the big black table-tennis board in the sky. Keep a spot open, so we can finish the game we never played, when my time comes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can send your condolences either in this blog&amp;rsquo;s comments or to the following&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nimesh: nimeshmaheshwari [at] gmail [dt] com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Priyanka: drmishrap [at] gmail [dt] com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
