<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shiv.me </title>
    <link>/tags/stasis/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2012-05-20 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>An hour with HAML and Stasis</title>
          <link>/2012/05/20/an-hour-with-haml-and-stasis/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
          <guid>/2012/05/20/an-hour-with-haml-and-stasis/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been meaning to get into the exciting world of static site-gen. Why, you ask? Well, I will tell you why?! Actually, I&amp;rsquo;m too lazy, and it&amp;rsquo;s late on a Sunday night &amp;ndash; instead, &lt;a href=&#34;http://mickgardner.com/&#34;&gt;Mick Gardner&lt;/a&gt;, can inform you on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mickgardner.com/2011/04/27/An-Introduction-To-Static-Site-Generators.html&#34;&gt;virtues of static site-generation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an hour of mucking around with several site-generators, I chose &lt;a href=&#34;http://stasis.me/&#34;&gt;Stasis&lt;/a&gt;, which is a good compromise to the blog-oriented &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, and options-insanity that is &lt;a href=&#34;http://nanoc.stoneship.org/&#34;&gt;nanoc&lt;/a&gt;. With my new-found fascination for Ruby, I wanted to stay away from &lt;a href=&#34;http://ringce.com/hyde&#34;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt; (which is Python based &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s time to try the dark-side, a little)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[HAML][6], is an interesting markup language. Although it cleanups some of the clutter of html, there are still things that are annoying. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTML:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HAML:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although, the HTML version has intrusive tags, it is easier on the eyes. It is a relief, not have to code, the end tag for every HTML element. It is much faster to type HAML by hand (especially in vim). In the end, it was a quick, painless process to convert the raw HTML code, to HAML, and generate the same html using stasis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life&amp;rsquo;s good. I&amp;rsquo;m still learning a few new tricks. What more can one ask for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[6]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://haml.info/&#34;&gt;http://haml.info/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
