<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>resolutions on Reflections</title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/resolutions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in resolutions on Reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2016 &amp;copy; Shivanand Velmurugan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 20:32:53 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.shiv.me/tags/resolutions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2016 year-end recap</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/12/31/2016-year-end-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 20:32:53 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/12/31/2016-year-end-recap/</guid>
      <description>Don’t smoke (Stay quit!!) : Doing great! There is no desire to smoke. After being a smoker for over a decade, I was very glad to quit, and stay quit. The way I quit this time was quite cliched. I went to Vegas, smoked incessantly for 3 days, and stopped at the end of the trip &amp;ndash; cold turkey. Never went back to it, and quite frankly disgusted by the thought of smoking now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A month flies by</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/01/31/jan-goal-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/01/31/jan-goal-update/</guid>
      <description>It has not been a great start. It, however, has been a busy one.
Don’t smoke (Stay quit!!) : Going strong! The urge to smoke still surfaces on occasion. I have, however, been able to avoid every time. I must admit that it gets easier, but it always take a bit of an effort.m
Say yes more often: Doing ok. I have caught myself a couple of times. Still needs work</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals for 2016</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/01/05/goals-for-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/01/05/goals-for-2016/</guid>
      <description>The word &amp;ldquo;resolutions&amp;rdquo;, feels forced. It feels like a ritual declaration of intent, followed immediately by inaction, and eventually concession that it was all in jest. This year, I am going to have some goals.
 Don’t smoke (Stay quit!!) Say yes more often Read a book a month Write an app a month Blog once a week  Goals, feels more friendly, reachable, inviting almost.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
