<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shiv.me </title>
    <link>/tags/se/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2007-01-25 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Trouble with Sony Ericsson W800i - Phone not detected.</title>
          <link>/2007/01/25/trouble-with-sony-ericsson-w800i---phone-not-detected./</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2007 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
          <guid>/2007/01/25/trouble-with-sony-ericsson-w800i---phone-not-detected./</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Trying to get the Sony Ericsson W800i has been by far the most traumatic experience of my life. I tried everything possible, but still was unable to get it recognised on my home PC!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, finally I decided to resort to the most reliable way to get anything to work with a PC. Do a google search!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Found a wonderful link, (on a forum that solved the issue). Here is the fix suggested, (I have organised in to be more of a step-by-step guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following involves tampering with the Windows Registry. Kindly take a BACKUP of your registry using regedit before attempting any changes. Oh yeah.. you are on your own in case you screw up something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EXPORT ALL THE KEYS MENTIONED BELOW BEFORE DELETING THEM! ALWAYS BEST TO HAVE A BACKUP&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure your phone is NOT connected to your computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run Regedit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browse to &amp;ldquo;My ComputerHKEY_LOCAL_MACHINESYSTEMCurrentControlSetEnumUSB&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete all key that start with &amp;ldquo;Vis_0fce&amp;amp;Pid_d028&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should be back to a stage where no w800 is installed on your machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download the drivers (Approved ones) from SE&amp;rsquo;s website under Support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the EXE file and let it install.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect your phone through the USB cable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to the orginal post can be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.expansys.com/ft.aspx?i=125173&amp;amp;thread=827&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
