<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google on shiv.me</title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/google/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google on shiv.me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2016 &amp;copy; Shivanand Velmurugan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.shiv.me/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>10 reasons to dump Facebook for G&#43;. Now!</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/08/28/10-reasons-to-dump-facebook-for-g&#43;.-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/08/28/10-reasons-to-dump-facebook-for-g&#43;.-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend asked what I like about google+, and as I started posting a reply , I noticed there were enough to make a blog post. So here goes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick list:&lt;br /&gt;
1. Mobile app on android and iphone are awesome!&lt;br /&gt;
2. Automatic upload of pics on phone/picasa&lt;br /&gt;
3. Non-crappy photos (allows 2400+px, and g+ renders pictures better, since they don&amp;rsquo;t mess with the image, if it is smaller than the max size)&lt;br /&gt;
4. Easier to mention specific people in a conversation. (auto-completes ppl&amp;rsquo;s profile name)&lt;br /&gt;
5. hangouts (free video conferencing)&lt;br /&gt;
6. Group messaging done right (huddle) on the mobile phone&lt;br /&gt;
7. decent integration with email (I guess this is just coz I use Gmail)&lt;br /&gt;
8. Privacy - predictable and manageable (not that it matters to me)&lt;br /&gt;
9. Much less noise (a - mostly used by techies for now, b - allows asymmetric relationships à la twitter)&lt;br /&gt;
10. Keyboard shortcuts (J, K work. Someone at google like vi &amp;ndash; a lot)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there&amp;rsquo;s 10 reasons to dump Facebook for G+. There is a lot more in terms of features (new ones are added all the time), but mostly the community is awesome, and the engagement is better!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11. (bonus). I was going to say games, but they have that here too, but I&amp;rsquo;m not bothered by it, and don&amp;rsquo;t have to see someone&amp;rsquo;s update on buying sheep&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said the above, I miss a couple of FB &amp;ldquo;features&amp;rdquo;. Really, its the of the same: 1. There is no way to start a conversation with someone, unless, you address it specifically to that person (in which case nobody else see it). Facebook does this simply, by providing a &amp;ldquo;wall&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. There are no &amp;ldquo;Groups&amp;rdquo;. Ie each circle is local to me, and hence, if I want to have a group for all my friends from university, I will have to add them to a circle. In order to simulate Facebook &amp;ldquo;groups&amp;rdquo;, everyone in that circle, has to add everyone else to a group of the same name. Adding one more person to that group, now means that everyone has to add that person manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure, google will come up with something to address the above two. We&amp;rsquo;ll have to wait and see how it goes!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So long and thanks for the &#34;jailed&#34; iphone</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/03/16/so-long-and-thanks-for-the-jailed-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/03/16/so-long-and-thanks-for-the-jailed-iphone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_737&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;]&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/wp-content/uploads/2010/03/Nexus-One-Phone-Choose-a-phone.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/images/Nexus-One-Phone-Choose-a-phone-300x195.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google Nexus is available in Canada&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; So long oppression[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the iPhone, Mr. Jobs. There is a new way to protest the iPhone. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/2010/02/04/ipad-is-ibad-petition/&#34;&gt;sign petitions&lt;/a&gt; anymore. I can now take my $500 &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/cXseFC&#34;&gt;elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;, for a slightly more open experience. I &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/2010/02/03/i-too-have-something-to-say-about-the-ipad/&#34;&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t ask for much&lt;/a&gt;, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait on your whim any longer (no offense meant to you personally, Mr Jobs).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And another thing about Google Buzz</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/02/10/and-another-thing-about-google-buzz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/02/10/and-another-thing-about-google-buzz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are several issues that people have uncovered in the last 2 days that it has existed. For me, of all the features that Buzz lacks, one thing really stands out. There is no way to just see a &lt;strong&gt;list of the conversations&lt;/strong&gt; (without the whole list of comments expanded by default). This is the main reason that I &lt;strong&gt;*had*&lt;/strong&gt; to unfollow Scoble, Michael Arrington, Louis Gray and a bunch of others. Take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/buzz/scobleizer/NE7yRrwbhbH/This-is-already-WAY-BETTER-than-FriendFeed-Why-Not&#34;&gt;this conversation&lt;/a&gt;, and you would understand why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time, anyone, replied to that thread (which incidently has been at the top of scoble&amp;rsquo;s buzz list all day), it would become the top post on my buzz view as well.  Now you are thinking, &amp;ldquo;Well, Buzz was not meant for long conversations&amp;rdquo;. Go back and read the comments on that conversation .. all 350+ of them, and come back here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note to Google Buzz Developers:&lt;/strong&gt; Now that truly sucks, and is such a trivial use-case that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if it gets fixed in a day or two &amp;hellip; it better if you want Scoble to continue to use it (and we all know how vital that is for any social network&amp;rsquo;s success).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s my humble request: PLEASE LET ME MINIMIZE HUGE-ASS THREADS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has already done this with Google Reader, where you can just see a list of items, or see them expanded. I don&amp;rsquo;t see any reason why this wasn&amp;rsquo;t the case, out of the box, for Buzz. In end, the only conclusion that I can think of is that, this pre-pre-alpha from a user experience perspective, and somehow all the design gurus (the ones who kept the Google page clean all these years), have disappeared into the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Buzz is by far, the clumsiest google product, with almost zero forethought to how users, will use it. It&amp;rsquo;s almost as if, none of the enigneers/designers on the Buzz have ever used twitter or facebook or friendfeed. Somehow I find that hard to believe. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping they&amp;rsquo;ll fix some, if not all the usability issues very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iterate guys! Iterate! Fast and hard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google likes RSS .. a lot</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/02/10/google-likes-rss-..-a-lot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/02/10/google-likes-rss-..-a-lot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Did anyone else notice that buzz has an RSS feed for everything!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/buzz/thomashawk22/Swv6u36BGC2/Buzz-should-let-you-post-inline-images-like-you&#34;&gt;conversation&lt;/a&gt; that @&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/profiles/thomashawk22#buzz&#34;&gt;Thomashawk&lt;/a&gt; started&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;feed://buzz.googleapis.com/feeds/104987932455782713675/comments/z12xt1zqbyjjcx44v04cdpjgjy34xxvg45k&#34;&gt;feed for that entry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the feed for &lt;a href=&#34;feed://buzz.googleapis.com/feeds/104987932455782713675/public/posted&#34;&gt;the owner&amp;rsquo;s entries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theoretically, one could build a service that aggregates only specific conversations (and keep them updated), or only a small group etc&amp;hellip; No more reading data from a firehose!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is very nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S: also this could be a way to aggregate all your webservices into one super feed, that can then be posted elsewhere (comments and all!!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power is endless, so be cautious when exercising it&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GReader just saved me a lot of time</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2009/08/14/greader-just-saved-me-a-lot-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2009/08/14/greader-just-saved-me-a-lot-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/shiva/TRAuLPzZpSXvJm4sA4jHJtcV6dkle25ltVlz8i8U5YFt2uOZ782tYHqdq6nE/greader.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/images/greader.jpg.scaled.500.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google reader is one of Google&amp;rsquo;s products, that didn&amp;rsquo;t you didn&amp;rsquo;t realize you needed until you started using it. Heck, pretty much every product they do is in that category. It is one app where I &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/reader/shared/shvelmur&#34;&gt;spend a lot of time every day&lt;/a&gt;. That is how I still manage to read blogs. Even after &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/shiva&#34;&gt;twitter &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&#34;http://facebook.com/shivanand&#34;&gt;facebook &lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&#34;http://friendfeed.com/shivanand&#34;&gt;friendfeed&lt;/a&gt;, GReader is still the place, where you can truly control the signal vs noise ratio of content that you read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, they have turned on a little feature that I have long pained for. It&amp;rsquo;s a little tweak, but a huge convenience. I tend to spend a few days away from reader once in a while, and when I come back, it&amp;rsquo;s a pain to filter out the content you want to read when you have 1000+ items. This little feature let&amp;rsquo;s me choose, which feeds I can ignore completely, which one, I need to read only the last week&amp;rsquo;s worth, etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you Google, for doing the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://posterous.com&#34;&gt;Posted via email&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://shiva.posterous.com/greader-just-saved-me-a-lot-of-time&#34;&gt;shiva&amp;rsquo;s posterous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For the last time, its not an OS!</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2009/07/09/for-the-last-time-its-not-an-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2009/07/09/for-the-last-time-its-not-an-os/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last couple of days has been ablaze with news of Google taking over the world, destroying Microsoft and sticking all of humanity on stakes to collect sunlight and convert it to power. Obviously, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/08/google-chrome-redefining-the-operating-system/&#34;&gt;some are elated at this proposition&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crunchgear.com/2009/07/08/a-third-opinion-on-google-chrome/&#34;&gt;some tentative&lt;/a&gt;, and then there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://fakesteve.blogspot.com/2009/07/lets-all-take-deep-breath-and-get-some.html&#34;&gt;some others&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://technosailor.com/2009/07/09/google-chrome-os-a-lot-to-do-about-nothing/&#34;&gt;who think all of this is just hogwash.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have but one thing to show you today. Presenting article number 1, a video by one of the minions at Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a tip: people on Times Square have no, frigging, clue of what a browser is. Don&amp;rsquo;t even get me started on, where the OS stops and the browser starts. The people you are trying to sell this to, don&amp;rsquo;t give a shit. The people who do know what a browser is, think you are just crap-shooting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, since I do know what a browser is, considering that I&amp;rsquo;ve used one since 95, I will say, that writing a shell on a linux kernel, and distributing it with only one app, does not make it an OS. It is a linux distro. I&amp;rsquo;m sure the following are familiar: Ubuntu, RedHat, Suse (Novell), which are all the same as Google Chrome (or atleast what they say it will be).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Google, stop &lt;a href=&#34;http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2009/07/introducing-google-chrome-os.html&#34;&gt;messing with things that don&amp;rsquo;t make you money&lt;/a&gt; and go fix that bug in Gmail or Google reader or maybe you can add RSS support to blogs on blogspot (the rest of the sane world did that only 5 years ago). We, who use your &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; ad-filled products will be very pleased. Oh yeah, while you are at it, figure out a way to &lt;a href=&#34;http://gigaom.com/2009/01/22/google-good-at-search-bad-at-investments/#comment-922970&#34;&gt;monetize those millions you invested&lt;/a&gt; in wonderful companies (Remember youtube, jaiku, jotspot, dodgeball, orkut, grandcentral ?! ). You might also want to consider improving this thing you helped invent &amp;ndash; search. I hear that there is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bing.com/&#34;&gt;new-comer&lt;/a&gt;. He sounds bad, and has a shitty name, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bing-vs-google.com/?q=google+chrome&#34;&gt;he&amp;rsquo;s getting better at it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, that&amp;rsquo;s it for today&amp;rsquo;s rant. Get off my lawn, I need to go google myself (Damn, this is therapeutic).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the browser lies the power - Wave 2 of the Google takeover</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/09/02/in-the-browser-lies-the-power---wave-2-of-the-google-takeover/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/09/02/in-the-browser-lies-the-power---wave-2-of-the-google-takeover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally it&amp;rsquo;s out in the open. The ultimate weapon in Google&amp;rsquo;s powerchest to combat desktop applications, render the need for a specific platform meaningless - the browser. I guess this has been in the making for the last decade, and here it is. A browser by a company that downloads pretty much most of the internet every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are still reading this, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be. Get outta here and &lt;a href=&#34;http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2008/09/fresh-take-on-browser.html#&#34;&gt;read this&lt;/a&gt;. (Actually just open in a new window, and continue reading this).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it makes a lot of sense for a company like Google to have an install base of their own, and what better way than, what has become the primary application on most computers, the browser. With Google&amp;rsquo;s data processing and storage capabilities, I can&amp;rsquo;t begin to imagine the things that could be done with a browser like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some unique things about (I stand corrected, David) Key features of Google Chrome (such a lame name .. come on guys you can be a bit more creative than that &amp;ndash; too many Mozilla hackers @ Google?!), as mentioned in their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/googlebooks/chrome/&#34;&gt;cartoon booklet&lt;/a&gt; (if you care to read thru 40 pages), include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tabs to the top (ignore that - such a cosmetic change) - Aparently this has been around for a while in Opera - thanks David Sheen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tabs as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/googlebooks/chrome/images/4.jpg&#34;&gt;separate processes&lt;/a&gt; (that&amp;rsquo;s good in a way, but I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure about older machines)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/googlebooks/chrome/images/7.jpg&#34;&gt;garbage collection engine. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/googlebooks/chrome/images/14.jpg&#34;&gt;javascript virtual machine&lt;/a&gt;, that supports &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/googlebooks/chrome/images/15.jpg&#34;&gt;compiled javascript&lt;/a&gt; - I want to see the performance on that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently, they have a huge testbed, that can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/googlebooks/chrome/images/10.jpg&#34;&gt;test each browser build&lt;/a&gt; automatically using a hundred monkeys. (I don&amp;rsquo;t care too much about this, I just think this is over-engineering, but hey, this is me).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/googlebooks/chrome/#&#34;&gt;Webkit for page-rendering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/googlebooks/chrome/images/18.jpg&#34;&gt;Persistant tab state&lt;/a&gt;, and the tab can be detached as well, into a new window.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standard &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/googlebooks/chrome/images/19.jpg&#34;&gt;auto-completing address bar&lt;/a&gt; (Firefox 3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personalised start page &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/googlebooks/chrome/images/21.jpg&#34;&gt;with your browsing history, google info etc.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a write this, a huge array of ideas come to mind, that will surely come to be common-place in next few years. I&amp;rsquo;m throwing out some general ideas here, and maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll come back a few years and tick some of them down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personalised homepages with per-user google content (this is already present in their beta vision)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single sign-on using open id and o-auth using google account information (read as identity management)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social networking (submit to orkut etc), location aware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voice calls from the browser (gtalk, jaiku etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content tagging services, using collective intelligence (this could make google searches much better than they already are - something like mahalo + google, just that every click could potentially give google data, thereby bettering the result match for you.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s my five things google could do. What do you think? What could Google add to their browser, that willl change the way we use it in the next 5 years?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google blogs its feature later than I do!</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2007/12/18/google-blogs-its-feature-later-than-i-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2007/12/18/google-blogs-its-feature-later-than-i-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I discovered today, that twitter+zooomr+a small utility called Cropper, now allows us to put new information about some of the products we use often, out into the blogosphere (I hate that word now), faster than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check this image that I posted this image on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zooomr.com/photos/shiva/3921233/&#34;&gt;zooomr on 12th Dec&lt;/a&gt; and then &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/shvelmur/statuses/494443532&#34;&gt;twittered it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/images/3921233_4558d6643d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a &lt;a href=&#34;http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/12/better-flight-stats-results.html&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, by (I presume) one of the engineer&amp;rsquo;s who made it happen, on the google&amp;rsquo;s official blog. Although, I didn&amp;rsquo;t post the exact feature he was talking about, I noticed the feature too on another search I was doing that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timing is becoming critical these days. Although, I guess more people out there learnt about the feature from his blog entry, it is becoming less relevant from the tech-crowd&amp;rsquo;s perspective. With guys like &lt;a href=&#34;http://scobleizer.com/&#34;&gt;Scoble&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techcrunch.com/about-michael-arrington/&#34;&gt;Mike&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scripting.com/stories/2007/02/21/daveWinerBio.html&#34;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;, it is quite tough &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techcrunch.com/2007/12/12/scoble-to-leave-podtech-heading-for-fast-company/&#34;&gt;keeping an announcement out of the crowds&lt;/a&gt; for long.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>