<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on Rabble-rousing Rambling</title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on Rabble-rousing Rambling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2016 &amp;copy; Shivanand Velmurugan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.shiv.me/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Piracy for convenience</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2012/01/16/piracy-for-convenience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2012/01/16/piracy-for-convenience/</guid>
      <description>In the wild days of 1996, when I got my hands on a computer (it cost about a year&amp;rsquo;s worth of my Dad&amp;rsquo;s salary, and nothing that I am would have been possible but for that sacrifice he made), I was enamored by the ease of content consumption on a computer.
In one year, I went from knowing nothing about the world, to interacting with hundreds of other people across the world, talking about different things, and experiencing new content every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>music and hearing</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/12/01/music-and-hearing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/12/01/music-and-hearing/</guid>
      <description>Forget perfect pitch. I&amp;rsquo;m so thankful that I can experience a large range of frequencies, and that I have enough hearing ability to distinguish timbre, and tone. Watch the video below, especially at 7:00 minutes. We all must be thankful that we can hear as well as we do. I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine what life would be like without the ability to sense the warmth of a viola rising up in the Brandenburg concertos (BWV 1046) movement 1, or the horns in the 3rd movement of the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music from DMU</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/01/11/music-from-dmu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/01/11/music-from-dmu/</guid>
      <description>DMU (Delete me Uncensored) is a group on Flickr, that was formed because a few people got pissed at Flickr censoring content. It is a very &amp;ldquo;lively&amp;rdquo; place on most days with a lot of colour and personality. Mostly its just a bunch of fine folks that have a common passion (photography), and express their opinions with almost no filters. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to mistake the group for being too rude, but you just have to hang around to &amp;lsquo;get it&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
