<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on shiv.me</title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on shiv.me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2016 &amp;copy; Shivanand Velmurugan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.shiv.me/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Elixir - A crash course</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/11/06/elixir-crash-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/11/06/elixir-crash-course/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post is a set of points I noted down, as I read through the Elixir documentation. This is by no means comprehensive. This is meant to be a crash course for someone coming from years of C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the content here, is simply a parsed summary of what is available as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://elixir-lang.org/getting-started/&#34;&gt;official documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;types&#34;&gt;Types&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;atoms&#34;&gt;Atoms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Named contants with a value. &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt; are atoms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;strings&#34;&gt;Strings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports unicode string natively! It&amp;rsquo;s about time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can concatenate strings using &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;hello&amp;quot; &amp;lt;&amp;gt; &amp;quot; world&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CAUTION&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;code&gt;byte_size(&amp;quot;hellö&amp;quot;) != String.length(&amp;quot;hellö&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CAUTION&lt;/em&gt;: (char list) &lt;code&gt;&#39;hello&#39; != &amp;quot;hello&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; (string)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;anonymous-functions&#34;&gt;Anonymous functions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Native support for closures &amp;ndash; called anonymous functions. Also, functions are first-class aka can be passed as arguments into other functions. Special syntax is required to invoke ananymous functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;iex(1)&amp;gt; add = fn a,b -&amp;gt; a + b end
#Function&amp;lt;12.52032458/2 in :erl_eval.expr/5&amp;gt;
iex(2)&amp;gt; add.(1,2)
3
iex(3)&amp;gt; mulby2 = fn a -&amp;gt; add.(a,a) end
#Function&amp;lt;6.52032458/1 in :erl_eval.expr/5&amp;gt;
iex(4)&amp;gt; mulby2.(4)
8
iex(5)&amp;gt; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lists&#34;&gt;Lists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Native support for lists. hd(list) and tl(list). A list of printable characters will be output as a string. Slower linear access to data, but really fast to prepend elements to the list. eg. &lt;code&gt;[ 0 | list]&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tuples&#34;&gt;Tuples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Native support for associative arrays. Any pair of values, stored contiguously. Indexes start from zero. mutable &lt;code&gt;put_elem(tuple, idx, &amp;quot;value&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;. Fast access, but expensive to add or insert elements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-types&#34;&gt;Other types&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Port, Reference and PID&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;operators&#34;&gt;Operators&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that ===, and !== use type when comparing (thankfully, the defaults are sensible)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;+, - , ++, &amp;ndash;, &amp;lt;&amp;gt; (concatenate)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and, or, not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;, ||, !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;==, !=, === (more strict), !== (more strict), &amp;lt;=, &amp;gt;=, &amp;lt; and &amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nil/false == false (everything else is true)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-match-operator&#34;&gt;The match operator (&lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used to assign result of an operation to a variable. Can also be used to assign a tuple or list to a set of variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{a, b, c} = {:hello, &amp;quot;world&amp;quot;, 42}
[a, b, c] = [1, 2, 3]
[head | tail] = [1, 2, 3]   # head = [1], tail = [2, 3]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-pin-operator&#34;&gt;The pin operator (&lt;code&gt;^&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Useful when there is a need to check one of the values of list, but assign another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;iex&amp;gt; x = 1
1
iex&amp;gt; x = 2
2
iex&amp;gt; x = 1
1
iex&amp;gt; ^x = 2
** (MatchError) no match of right hand side value: 2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-operator&#34;&gt;The _ operator&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ignore the rest, or assign the rest to _&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iex&amp;gt; [h | _] = [1, 2, 3]
[1, 2, 3]
iex&amp;gt; h
1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;control-structures-conditionals-and-loops&#34;&gt;Control Structures (conditionals and loops)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;case - check for multiple matches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cond - check for multiple conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if, else, end - check for specific condition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;unless - check for a specific match&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: if and unless are macros and not first class constructs that are part of the language&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elixir allows a lot of variations of guards that are used in conditional to express conditions. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://elixir-lang.org/getting-started/case-cond-and-if.html#expressions-in-guard-clauses&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;do/end - the syntax is a bit weird, but quite similar to do..while in C&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;iex&amp;gt; if true, do: 1 + 2
3
iex&amp;gt; if false, do: :this, else: :that
:that
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following are equivalent aka &lt;code&gt;end&lt;/code&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;iex&amp;gt; if true do
...&amp;gt;   a = 1 + 2
...&amp;gt;   a + 10
...&amp;gt; end
13
iex&amp;gt; if true, do: (
...&amp;gt;   a = 1 + 2
...&amp;gt;   a + 10
...&amp;gt; )
13
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following would result in a parsing error (is_number that takes two args &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; is not found)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;iex&amp;gt; is_number if true do
...&amp;gt;  1 + 2
...&amp;gt; end
** (CompileError) undefined function: is_number/2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would be the correct way to acheive the normally &amp;ldquo;expected&amp;rdquo; behaviour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;iex&amp;gt; is_number(if true do
...&amp;gt;  1 + 2
...&amp;gt; end)
true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Linux, learn new things</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/07/10/use-linux-learn-new-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/07/10/use-linux-learn-new-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After 12+ years, I built a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ca.pcpartpicker.com/b/j6Cypg&#34;&gt;workstation from scratch&lt;/a&gt;. Hardware has come such a long way, but that is a post unto itself. Having always worked with Ubuntu and other debian variants it was time to venture into a more lean distro. I picked &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/arch_compared_to_other_distributions&#34;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt;, on the recommendation of several colleagues. It&amp;rsquo;s been fun. &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.archlinux.org/index.php/pacman&#34;&gt;Pacman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://archlinux.fr/yaourt-en&#34;&gt;Yaourt&lt;/a&gt; are great package managers, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rolling_release&#34;&gt;rolling release&lt;/a&gt; model ensures access to the bleeding edge all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working in linux always makes you learn something new. Today, I found out a simple way to shutdown KDE gracefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# qdbus org.kde.ksmserver /KSMServer logout 0 0 0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battle of the static site generators - part 1</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/02/10/battle-of-the-static-site-generators-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/02/10/battle-of-the-static-site-generators-1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I set myself a goal to write more this year - in fact, I attempted to do so once every week. This required me to look at my blog, which led to the inevitable: small changes in what it looked like, led to general dis-satisfcation with the current solution I have to publish my blog, which quickly ballooned into a whole host of activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me step back a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jekyll-is-really-hyde&#34;&gt;Jekyll is really Hyde&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I host my blog on github, using a static site generator - Jekyll. It is written in ruby, has some cool features. Overall, it is a decent solution, but I was never satisfied with options it provided. I have hesistated to hack at it, since ruby isn&amp;rsquo;t my language-du-jour, and most of the changes have been quite minimal. It is also extremely slow&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As any self-respecting programmer is wont to do, instead of writing more posts, and meeting my goal, I delved right into fixing &amp;ldquo;bike-shed&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; in this case, research and use a new static-site generator. Why, you ask? To you, non-existent, ever-questioning inquisitive you, I say &amp;ndash; Why not?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any successful hunt, one &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; make a list: One that shall help determine settle the battle of the generators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must be &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; I mean blazing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must be in one of the languages I currently hack in: go, nim, c, c++, javascript, python, rust, erlang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should have good defaults &amp;ndash; shouldn&amp;rsquo;t need plugins to perform basic features: syntax highlighting, responsive images, theming,
 permalinks and good markdown support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should have a few good themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good community support and/or documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-contenders&#34;&gt;The contenders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scouring the corners of the internet, I narrowed down on two final choices: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hexo.io/&#34;&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-shiny-shiny&#34;&gt;New shiny, shiny&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They
   - are faster at generating 300+ pages.
   - are opinionated and hence have good defaults.
   - support most of features I am looking for except responsive images.
   - provide extended markdown support by default.
   - hosted by an active community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo-ftw&#34;&gt;Hugo FTW!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Hugo and Hexo are pretty good. They are fast enough for my use, and are implemented in modern languages that I am actively learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo edged out Hexo: It has a few features that look promising and is a bit more fun to hack. It is written in go and this make it ideal. I am switching to Go as a primary language for my hacking needs. A lot of issues, and about 3000 forks is a good opportunity to contribute to a larg-ish project in go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choice is made. Now to move the herd. I have the daunting task of migrating 300+ posts that were originally posted on different blog engines of the past: blogger, wordpress, and octopress and finally jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In subsequent posts, I will write about a small tool I have built to help with fixing YAML frontmatter after converting posts from html to markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;Slow is relative. I have about 300+ posts, and rendering them into HTML using jekyll, takes a few minutes.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A month flies by</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/01/31/jan-goal-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/01/31/jan-goal-update/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It has not been a great start. It, however, has been a busy one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-smoke-stay-quit-going-strong&#34;&gt;Don’t smoke (Stay quit!!) : Going strong!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The urge to smoke still surfaces on occasion. I have, however, been able to avoid every time. I must admit that it gets easier, but it always take a bit of an effort.m&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;say-yes-more-often-doing-ok&#34;&gt;Say yes more often: Doing ok.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have caught myself a couple of times. Still needs work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;read-a-book-a-month-failing-miserably&#34;&gt;Read a book a month: Failing miserably.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read about 5 pages. Currently reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1PI7fTC&#34;&gt;Norwegian Wood&lt;/a&gt; by Haruki Murakami. It is a very interesting book, but I have not been able to find time consistently. TV, netflix and youtube, usurps time away from other pursuits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;write-an-app-a-month-doing-ok&#34;&gt;Write an app a month: Doing ok.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have managed to write a small app to collect links and text and store those into a database. The app is written in go and is called notedown. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun to hack something together. I am struggling with user authentication and authorization. &lt;a href=&#34;https://auth0.com/&#34;&gt;auth0&lt;/a&gt; is a great service to get started with implementing a good system for any app. At the moment, I have managed to put together a very rough version that kinda works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, the goal is to get parity with apps like instapaper or evernote. The eventual goal, is to make notedown provide automatic tagging and aggregation of links. For the next month, I will focus on getting this solution deployed with a simple gui that is cross-platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in the idea, you can reach me on &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/shiva&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitter.im/shiva/notedown?utm_source=badge&amp;amp;utm_medium=badge&amp;amp;utm_campaign=pr-badge&#34;&gt;Gitter&lt;/a&gt; or hack at it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/shiva/notedown&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blog-once-a-week-failing-miserably&#34;&gt;Blog once a week: Failing miserably.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this post illustrates, I have procrastinated all month long. I guess two posts a month is still better than none.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goals for 2016</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/01/05/goals-for-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/01/05/goals-for-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The word &amp;ldquo;resolutions&amp;rdquo;, feels forced. It feels like a ritual declaration of intent, followed immediately by inaction, and eventually concession that it was all in jest. This year, I am going to have some goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t smoke (Stay quit!!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say yes more often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read a book a month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write an app a month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog once a week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goals, feels more friendly, reachable, inviting almost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on ello</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/09/30/thoughts-on-ello/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/09/30/thoughts-on-ello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the tradition of joining new social tools on the interwebs, here some thoughts on my experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The usual steps are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first few hours &amp;ndash; mostly spent exploring the interface, the features, mired in the comparisons between the &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At some point, the lack of interaction and content of previous networks &amp;ndash; the constant buzz of twitter, the inane conversations of facebook etc. &amp;ndash; forces me tp  hunt for connections. Rampant, indiscriminate &amp;ldquo;friending&amp;rdquo; of people ensues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Invite a few select people, find the &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; connections from elsewhere, and waddle in the familiarity of all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Crickets .. not a thing is said. I realize I have nothing to say most days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start contributing content, and attempt to find the niche for this medium&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;All my kindergarden, high school and college buddies arrive, and make their presence felt&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get lazy and stop contributing - the content feed become a wasteland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just about done with 3 on ello. It&amp;rsquo;s is going to a fun experience! Of that, I am sure. Some things I like on Ello, that I hope will break the pattern of &amp;ldquo;use-discard&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keyboard shortcuts!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Friends/Noise. This is a great middle ground between the insanity that is Circles on Google+, the unmaintainable mess that is twitter lists, and the unknowable grouping in FB.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Multiple layout options. Makes the incessant updates manageable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Markdown. Can&amp;rsquo;t thank the developers of Ello, enough for this!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ability to cross-post content between my blog and Ello. Thanks largely, to markdown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some posts from others more articulate than me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@thomashawk quips on &lt;a href=&#34;https://ello.co/thomashawk/post/yTBdvFtgsjFuv6gi3kWy-A&#34;&gt;his thoughts on Ello&lt;/a&gt;. A great read. As always, TH has great content, and also copious amounts of patience in letting such tools grow, and helping it in the process (I&amp;rsquo;ve seen him do this for flickr, google+ and zooomr).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@budnitz One of the founders of Ello &lt;a href=&#34;https://ello.co/budnitz/post/WDPYMs2EvyUqUtDh5lAOiA&#34;&gt;makes great points&lt;/a&gt; on starting up something new. Nice to see the passion and the vision. Kudos!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ello.co/shivanand/post/y7Kwrh64mViqEgRNg_OV2g&#34;&gt;Cross-posted on Ello&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Eiffel Tower</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/07/15/my-eiffel-tower/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/07/15/my-eiffel-tower/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2014/07/lessons-from-the-eiffel-tower.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Fsethsmainblog+%28Seth%27s+Blog%29&#34;&gt;post by Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;, struck a cord. I am fortunate enough to get an opportunity to build &amp;ldquo;my Eiffel Tower&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m building two DSLs and associated infrastructure to allow storing lots of data in an in-memory database running in an embedded system. Wish me luck! Very excited, I might add!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting rid of passwords</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/07/14/getting-rid-of-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/07/14/getting-rid-of-passwords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hate passwords. Seems like several smart people are on the case of getting rid of the &amp;ldquo;password&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lucas Gonze, argues the &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@lucas_gonze/authentication-cargo-cults-ae98d8e359&#34;&gt;loss of meaning&lt;/a&gt; around design of user authentication mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A world without passwords! How will we identify each other? &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ninjudd/passwords-are-obsolete-9ed56d483eb&#34;&gt;Exchange tokens&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.cotap.com/forget-passwords-passwordless-authentication/&#34;&gt;Make &amp;ldquo;forgot password&amp;rdquo; the default&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@gwestr/trust-without-passwords-c91146a96cef&#34;&gt;Passwords are the new pay-wall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A non-violent protest against the cruel overlord &amp;mdash; the &amp;ldquo;password&amp;rdquo;. Justin Balthrop, &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ninjudd/lets-boycott-passwords-680d97eddb01&#34;&gt;calls for a boycott&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://notes.xoxco.com/post/27999787765/is-it-time-for-password-less-login&#34;&gt;Several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://notes.xoxco.com/post/28288684632/more-on-password-less-login&#34;&gt;alternatives&lt;/a&gt; to identify users &amp;mdash; promoting password-less login in your apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eran Hammer &amp;mdash; OAuth founder &amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;http://hueniverse.com/2012/07/26/oauth-2-0-and-the-road-to-hell/&#34;&gt;gave up on OAuth 2.0&lt;/a&gt;. (An old link). Tim Bray &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2012/07/28/Oauth2-dead&#34;&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t take kindly&lt;/a&gt; to that post. Ahh IETF! You can grind the smartest minds to pulp. :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ink rotation - April 2014</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/04/23/ink-rotation-april-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/04/23/ink-rotation-april-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t been very good with rotating the inks in the last year. Having accumulated more than my share of inks, it is time to have fewer pens inked and rotate colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/images/20140423-085227.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20140423-085227.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist inking 9 pens! There are 3 pens I&amp;rsquo;m excited about &amp;ndash; 2 parker 51 and a custom pen made out of 10000 year-old bogwood (a gift from &lt;a href=&#34;http://tinaferan.com&#34;&gt;Christina&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/images/20140423-085350.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20140423-085350.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting git status on multiple directories</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/03/31/getting-git-status-on-multiple-directories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/03/31/getting-git-status-on-multiple-directories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At any given time, I have a handful of git repositories that I work on. While typing in the command-line is great, it getting tiring when you have a several directories that you have to manually change to and check. The &amp;ldquo;git status&amp;rdquo; command can take the git repo and the working directory as input. That, and a little bash programming to the rescue.
The following command, executes git status in every subdirectory that is a git repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;for d in `find . -name &amp;quot;.git&amp;quot;`; do 
echo &amp;quot;processing $d ...&amp;quot;; 
git --git-dir=$d --work-tree=$d/.. status; 
done
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Somethings should be obvious, but are not, obviously</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/02/14/somethings-should-be-obvious-but-are-not-obviously/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/02/14/somethings-should-be-obvious-but-are-not-obviously/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: Apparently, I had accidentally hit a minor bug in pew. This has now been &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/berdario/invewrapper/issues/21&#34;&gt;fixed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every so often, we spend several hours battling an issue, fighting linux or python or people or thoughts. The solution, often, leaps out when there has been a respite in the constant search for the solution. It&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;duh&amp;rdquo; moment, that all of us feel. There is a little self-loathing, and relief at having arrived at solution. It is a moment of great pleasure, that I have learned to relish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently on a bit of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.org/&#34;&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt; binge, and I was setting up a dev environment, using &lt;a href=&#34;http://crunchbang.org/&#34;&gt;Crunchbang&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virtualbox.org/&#34;&gt;Virtualbox&lt;/a&gt;. Since it is a clean install, I wanted to bootstrap using only &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/berdario/invewrapper&#34;&gt;pew&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pip-installer.org/en/latest/&#34;&gt;pip&lt;/a&gt;, which have recently become my favourite part of working in a pure python environment (no more sudo == yay!!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I followed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/berdario/invewrapper#installation&#34;&gt;instructions to install pew&lt;/a&gt; (which is quite straight-forward). All one should need is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;    pip install pew
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when I tried the same, the install worked, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t run pew. It couldn&amp;rsquo;t find all the libraries it needed to load (virtualenv, in this case)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;    shiva@crunchbang-2:~$ sudo pip install pew
    Downloading/unpacking pew
    Downloading pew-0.1.9.tar.gz
    Running setup.py (path:/tmp/pip_build_root/pew/setup.py) egg_info for package pew
    ...
    Successfully installed pew virtualenv
    Cleaning up...
    
    shiva@crunchbang-2:~$ pew ls
    Traceback (most recent call last):
    File &amp;quot;/usr/local/bin/pew&amp;quot;, line 5, in
    from pkg_resources import load_entry_point
    File &amp;quot;/usr/lib/python2.7/dist-packages/pkg_resources.py&amp;quot;, line 2707, in
    working_set.require(__requires__)
    File &amp;quot;/usr/lib/python2.7/dist-packages/pkg_resources.py&amp;quot;, line 686, in require
    needed = self.resolve(parse_requirements(requirements))
    File &amp;quot;/usr/lib/python2.7/dist-packages/pkg_resources.py&amp;quot;, line 584, in resolve
    raise DistributionNotFound(req)
    pkg_resources.DistributionNotFound: virtualenv
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After trying several things, including looking a lot of code in pew, the fix was quite simple.
The version of setup-tools that comes default with python2.7 and crunchbang seems flawed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;    shiva@crunchbang-2:~$ sudo pip install -U setuptools
    Downloading/unpacking setuptools from https://pypi.python.org/packages/3.4/s/setuptools/setuptools-2.2-py2.py3-none-any.whl#md5=3b7d84f496aed8c07b91efba4aa197a4
    Downloading setuptools-2.2-py2.py3-none-any.whl (540kB): 540kB downloaded
    Installing collected packages: setuptools
    Found existing installation: distribute 0.6.24dev-r0
    Uninstalling distribute:
    Successfully uninstalled distribute
    Successfully installed setuptools
    Cleaning up...
    
    shiva@crunchbang-2:~$ pew ls
    
    shiva@crunchbang-2:~$ pew new test
    New python executable in test/bin/python
    Installing setuptools, pip...done.
    Launching subshell in virtual environment. Type &#39;exit&#39; or &#39;Ctrl+D&#39; to return.
    /home/shiva/.local/share/virtualenvs/test/bin:/home/shiva/bin:/usr/sbin:/sbin:/usr/local/bin:/usr/bin:/bin:/usr/local/games:/usr/games
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoins, new languages, freedom and other things</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/01/27/bitcoins-new-languages-freedom-and-other-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/01/27/bitcoins-new-languages-freedom-and-other-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some interesting links for the weekend:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mr.Krugman thinks &lt;a href=&#34;http://krugman.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/12/28/bitcoin-is-evil/&#34;&gt;Bitcoin is evil.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why should &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/11/27/disruptions-fliers-must-turn-off-devices-but-its-not-clear-why/?_r=0&#34;&gt;turn off my devices for 30 mins&lt;/a&gt;, while a hunk of steel and glass is hurled into the upper atmosphere? #first-world-problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lambda-the-ultimate.org/node/4862&#34;&gt;Lamdba expressions&lt;/a&gt;: something for the nerd in you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;America, you make me want to travel! &lt;a href=&#34;http://reason.com/archives/2013/12/28/americas-internal-checkpoints&#34;&gt;NOT REALLY!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t really change. &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/p/defd9264bf14&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not blame it on tech&lt;/a&gt;! Truth from Gary Vaynerchuk of winelibrary fame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Those wonderful tele-conference meetings</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/01/25/those-wonderful-tele-conference-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/01/25/those-wonderful-tele-conference-meetings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have worked for a large company, you know you have been here. Hilarious&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/DYu_bGbZiiQ&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2013 on twitter - a recap</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/01/02/2013-on-twitter---a-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2014/01/02/2013-on-twitter---a-recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vizify.com/&#34;&gt;Vizify&lt;/a&gt; makes a video out of the posts you have made on twitter in the last year. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tinaferan&#34;&gt;Christina&lt;/a&gt;, you are always my #1! Thank you for bringing this to my attention. As any self-respecting nerd would do, I immediately made one for myself. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t the world need yet another summary of meee!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vizify.com/shivanand/twitter-video&#34;&gt;2013 on twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my top followers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tinaferan&#34;&gt;Christina&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ray_lian&#34;&gt;Ray Lian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/covivant&#34;&gt;Dave Kell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malaise of large companies</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2013/12/28/malaise-of-large-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2013/12/28/malaise-of-large-companies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://scripting.com/2013/12/28/microsoftAndNetbooks.html&#34;&gt;Another gem&lt;/a&gt; from the always spot-on Dave Winer. Microsoft could have owned netbooks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pathological need for large companies to focus on the wrong, to their own demise never ceases to amaze me. Why do dominant players lose out? Is it the incompetence of people in these companies? Is it the inability to articulate, convince, and move the masses within these companies?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most often, it is the later. Perhaps, the collective, is bound to make safer choices and very often, the simple or obvious option is not the safe one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It always comes down to doing the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ulrichsossou.com/2012/07/13/easy-vs-simple/&#34;&gt;simple vs the easy&lt;/a&gt;. Simple is hard!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S: I work for a large company. It is a daily struggle, irrespective of the domain of the choice &amp;ndash; design, code or cultural.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>