<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Plugins on shiv.me</title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/plugins/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Plugins on shiv.me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2016 &amp;copy; Shivanand Velmurugan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.shiv.me/tags/plugins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>EX-SideRSS</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2007/10/01/ex-siderss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2007/10/01/ex-siderss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After several months of keeping away from updating or changing my website, I broke the fast today. I found a wonderful plugin, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.underjc.com/?q=node/13&#34;&gt;sideRSS&lt;/a&gt;, which allows display of RSS feeds within a blog&amp;rsquo;s sidebar. As usual, I needed a specific functionality that was not supported the way I wanted it. I hacked it a little bit, renamed the plugin, and posted a custom version for download on my website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to share Google Shared Items, on your blog, but hate to include javascript (like I do), then use this. You can download it &lt;a href=&#34;http://shvelmur.com/downloads/projects/ex-siderss.php&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (right-click and use &amp;ldquo;Save Target As&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;) and find install information &lt;a href=&#34;http://shvelmur.com/wpress/projects/exsiderss/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you like this version, and would like me to add a few more features (I have some in mind though, like ATOM parsing), do suggest them in the comments section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S: If you are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.underjc.com/&#34;&gt;Chris Hatcher&lt;/a&gt;, the author of the original &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.underjc.com/?q=node/13&#34;&gt;SideRSS&lt;/a&gt;, and want to take this version down or something, just leave a message here - you will need to merge my changes in your code though :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technorati Tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://technorati.com/tags/EX-SideRSS&#34;&gt;EXSideRSS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://technorati.com/tags/SideRSS&#34;&gt;SideRSS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://technorati.com/tags/wordpress%20plugins&#34;&gt;wordpress plugins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Access Portal</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2007/01/20/common-access-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2007/01/20/common-access-portal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With advent of web 2.0, and some habits cultivated over the last decade, I have a certain list of tasks that I do everyday. I current visit a bunch of websites more than once a day, and an integrated interface would do me so much good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mail, a whole set of accounts, gmail, yahoo, etc&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feed readers&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blog editor&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;orkut&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;del.icio&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;google notebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is lacking, is the ability to have a single sign-on/account mgmt capability, a common dashboard, ability to cross-launch/cross-post content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ohh yeah, I want to do thiss all from either my desktop or from my own hosted page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there are some deep implicating requirements for my latest craze - get more done with less clicks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I christen it Common Access Portal (Let&amp;rsquo;s put a CAP on things we use!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>