<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mac OSX on Rabble-rousing Rambling</title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/mac-osx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mac OSX on Rabble-rousing Rambling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2016 &amp;copy; Shivanand Velmurugan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.shiv.me/tags/mac-osx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OSX Lion. A first look (at 2 AM)</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/07/23/osx-lion.-a-first-look-at-2-am/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/07/23/osx-lion.-a-first-look-at-2-am/</guid>
      <description>Just upgraded to OSX Lion. A very slick interface.
Quick Review:
1. Launchpad. Solved previously by Alfred in the GUI, and bash aliases on the command line.
2. Mission Control. Eye-candy. Will probably use it until I get tired of all the moving windows, and stick to Cmd+arrow keys to switch desktops. Maybe normal users will find it useful. But then, most people don&amp;rsquo;t want anything that increases their workflow complexity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m getting an os upgrade for 10 bucks!</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2009/08/28/im-getting-an-os-upgrade-for-10-bucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2009/08/28/im-getting-an-os-upgrade-for-10-bucks/</guid>
      <description>With Snow Leopard, Apple has the first time done something that has made me go wow! An almost free OS upgrade. This kinda beats the crap out of paying a couple hundred for Win7.
Posted via email from shiva&amp;rsquo;s posterous</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biting the &#34;Mac&#34; Bullet</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/03/15/biting-the-mac-bullet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/03/15/biting-the-mac-bullet/</guid>
      <description>I did it! I finally went out and bought myself a mac. I didn&amp;rsquo;t waver. No! Not this time.Â I knew exactly what I wanted, and I was going to get it, come what may!
I have to confess that I have been pretty critical of Apple andits policies. I still am. Nothing has changed my opinion of Apple as a company, in particular, it&amp;rsquo;s marketing team. The ipod touch price changes lead me to those conclusions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
