<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shiv.me </title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/10-reasons/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2011-08-28 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>10 reasons to dump Facebook for G&#43;. Now!</title>
          <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/08/28/10-reasons-to-dump-facebook-for-g.-now/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
          <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/08/28/10-reasons-to-dump-facebook-for-g.-now/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend asked what I like about google+, and as I started posting a reply , I noticed there were enough to make a blog post. So here goes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick list:&lt;br /&gt;
1. Mobile app on android and iphone are awesome!&lt;br /&gt;
2. Automatic upload of pics on phone/picasa&lt;br /&gt;
3. Non-crappy photos (allows 2400+px, and g+ renders pictures better, since they don&amp;rsquo;t mess with the image, if it is smaller than the max size)&lt;br /&gt;
4. Easier to mention specific people in a conversation. (auto-completes ppl&amp;rsquo;s profile name)&lt;br /&gt;
5. hangouts (free video conferencing)&lt;br /&gt;
6. Group messaging done right (huddle) on the mobile phone&lt;br /&gt;
7. decent integration with email (I guess this is just coz I use Gmail)&lt;br /&gt;
8. Privacy - predictable and manageable (not that it matters to me)&lt;br /&gt;
9. Much less noise (a - mostly used by techies for now, b - allows asymmetric relationships à la twitter)&lt;br /&gt;
10. Keyboard shortcuts (J, K work. Someone at google like vi &amp;ndash; a lot)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there&amp;rsquo;s 10 reasons to dump Facebook for G+. There is a lot more in terms of features (new ones are added all the time), but mostly the community is awesome, and the engagement is better!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11. (bonus). I was going to say games, but they have that here too, but I&amp;rsquo;m not bothered by it, and don&amp;rsquo;t have to see someone&amp;rsquo;s update on buying sheep&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said the above, I miss a couple of FB &amp;ldquo;features&amp;rdquo;. Really, its the of the same: 1. There is no way to start a conversation with someone, unless, you address it specifically to that person (in which case nobody else see it). Facebook does this simply, by providing a &amp;ldquo;wall&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. There are no &amp;ldquo;Groups&amp;rdquo;. Ie each circle is local to me, and hence, if I want to have a group for all my friends from university, I will have to add them to a circle. In order to simulate Facebook &amp;ldquo;groups&amp;rdquo;, everyone in that circle, has to add everyone else to a group of the same name. Adding one more person to that group, now means that everyone has to add that person manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure, google will come up with something to address the above two. We&amp;rsquo;ll have to wait and see how it goes!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
