<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>recipe on Rabble-rousing Rambling</title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/recipe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in recipe on Rabble-rousing Rambling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2016 &amp;copy; Shivanand Velmurugan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.shiv.me/tags/recipe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prawn curry</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/12/14/prawn-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/12/14/prawn-curry/</guid>
      <description>If you are in a hurry, and need something tasty yet easy to make, this one is for you. The prep time is about 5 minutes, and the cooking time around 10-15 minutes. If you have a small rice cooker &amp;ndash; the kind that plugs into a wall sockets &amp;ndash; you should be able to get the rice done in about the same time.
It is also the perfect curry to cook for smaller portions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tandoori spiced fish with cucumber</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/09/25/tandoori-spiced-fish-with-cucumber/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/09/25/tandoori-spiced-fish-with-cucumber/</guid>
      <description>One program&amp;ndash;on Food TV&amp;ndash;that I like to watch, is Gordon Ramsey&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen Nightmares. He is such a powerful person, who is into what he does for a living. He has inspired me to get of my couch and cook decent food.
This is a recipe from his book, Fast Food. Every guy who wants to cook decent food should have on his shelf. A simple book, with simple recipes that any idiot (aka me) can follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Curry with Eggs served on Rice</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/08/04/chicken-curry-with-eggs-served-on-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/08/04/chicken-curry-with-eggs-served-on-rice/</guid>
      <description>Chicken Curry with Eggs served on Rice, originally uploaded by Shivanand Velmurugan.

Thank you Mr. Raghavan Iyer. This is the man, that wrote the book 660 Curries, that has initiated me into making proper Indian food. In the last month or so, since my return from my vacation to India, I have tried eating good food, and have found cooking a very rewarding activity. It helps you think more about what you want to put in your mouth and somehow, also makes you eat less!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
