<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shiv.me </title>
    <link>/tags/google-buzz/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2010-02-10 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>And another thing about Google Buzz</title>
          <link>/2010/02/and-another-thing-about-google-buzz/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
          <guid>/2010/02/and-another-thing-about-google-buzz/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There are several issues that people have uncovered in the last 2 days that it has existed. For me, of all the features that Buzz lacks, one thing really stands out. There is no way to just see a &lt;strong&gt;list of the conversations&lt;/strong&gt; (without the whole list of comments expanded by default). This is the main reason that I &lt;strong&gt;*had*&lt;/strong&gt; to unfollow Scoble, Michael Arrington, Louis Gray and a bunch of others. Take a look at [this conversation][0], and you would understand why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time, anyone, replied to that thread (which incidently has been at the top of scoble&amp;rsquo;s buzz list all day), it would become the top post on my buzz view as well.  Now you are thinking, &amp;ldquo;Well, Buzz was not meant for long conversations&amp;rdquo;. Go back and read the comments on that conversation .. all 350+ of them, and come back here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note to Google Buzz Developers:&lt;/strong&gt; Now that truly sucks, and is such a trivial use-case that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if it gets fixed in a day or two &amp;hellip; it better if you want Scoble to continue to use it (and we all know how vital that is for any social network&amp;rsquo;s success).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s my humble request: PLEASE LET ME MINIMIZE HUGE-ASS THREADS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has already done this with Google Reader, where you can just see a list of items, or see them expanded. I don&amp;rsquo;t see any reason why this wasn&amp;rsquo;t the case, out of the box, for Buzz. In end, the only conclusion that I can think of is that, this pre-pre-alpha from a user experience perspective, and somehow all the design gurus (the ones who kept the Google page clean all these years), have disappeared into the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Buzz is by far, the clumsiest google product, with almost zero forethought to how users, will use it. It&amp;rsquo;s almost as if, none of the enigneers/designers on the Buzz have ever used twitter or facebook or friendfeed. Somehow I find that hard to believe. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping they&amp;rsquo;ll fix some, if not all the usability issues very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iterate guys! Iterate! Fast and hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/buzz/scobleizer/NE7yRrwbhbH/This-is-already-WAY-BETTER-than-FriendFeed-Why-Not&#34;&gt;http://www.google.com/buzz/scobleizer/NE7yRrwbhbH/This-is-already-WAY-BETTER-than-FriendFeed-Why-Not&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Google likes RSS .. a lot</title>
          <link>/2010/02/google-likes-rss-..-a-lot/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
          <guid>/2010/02/google-likes-rss-..-a-lot/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Did anyone else notice that buzz has an RSS feed for everything!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/buzz/thomashawk22/Swv6u36BGC2/Buzz-should-let-you-post-inline-images-like-you&#34;&gt;conversation&lt;/a&gt; that @&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/profiles/thomashawk22#buzz&#34;&gt;Thomashawk&lt;/a&gt; started&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;feed://buzz.googleapis.com/feeds/104987932455782713675/comments/z12xt1zqbyjjcx44v04cdpjgjy34xxvg45k&#34;&gt;feed for that entry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the feed for [the owner&amp;rsquo;s entries][3]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theoretically, one could build a service that aggregates only specific conversations (and keep them updated), or only a small group etc&amp;hellip; No more reading data from a firehose!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is very nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S: also this could be a way to aggregate all your webservices into one super feed, that can then be posted elsewhere (comments and all!!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power is endless, so be cautious when exercising it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]: feed://buzz.googleapis.com/feeds/104987932455782713675/public/posted&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
