<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Reflections</title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2016 &amp;copy; Shivanand Velmurugan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.shiv.me/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes, they are useful for a lifetime</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/09/25/sometimes-they-are-useful-for-a-lifetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/09/25/sometimes-they-are-useful-for-a-lifetime/</guid>
      <description>And sometimes, they barely hold your attention. However, the recent acquisition is the former. I got the mammoth of a book, over the weekend; it weighs a ton and I&amp;rsquo;ll be sleeping with it, clutched tight in my hands.
If you already have the tomb by tanenbaum of similar name, the unix programming interface, you probably are not going to glean much value from this one (you can thank POSIX for maintaining a modicum of consistency over the years and some would vehemently contest that).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guess what I&#39;m getting in a week or two?!</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2009/10/14/guess-what-im-getting-in-a-week-or-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2009/10/14/guess-what-im-getting-in-a-week-or-two/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for this for a while now! Gary I hope it is all that I expect it to be. If I don&amp;rsquo;t read this the day I get it, and jump up from my bed at 2 AM crying &amp;ldquo;crush it&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; well &amp;hellip; I bet I will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: A Year in the Merde by Stephen Clarke</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2009/01/02/review-a-year-in-the-merde-by-stephen-clarke/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2009/01/02/review-a-year-in-the-merde-by-stephen-clarke/</guid>
      <description>A Year in the Merde by Stephen Clarke
rating: 5 of 5 stars
If you are on your way to Paris, or on the way from Paris, or in Paris, or &amp;hellip; nevermind&amp;hellip; just read this book if you are associated, in any way, with Paris. You&amp;rsquo;ll love it.
(If you are French, read this too, get angry, rebel and then revel in the glory! :) )
View all my reviews at goodreads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SNMP tutorials</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2005/10/06/snmp-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2005/10/06/snmp-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>SNMP being the bread and butter for me, I decided to dig up some tutorials and links regarding the same.
For the uninitiated, SNMP is short for Simple Network Management Protocol, and is a protocol used to manage network devices such as routers, switches etc.
 Simple Web - Introduction to SNMP, and good set of tutorials Simple Times - technical articles and featured columns Cisco - SNMP Overview Cisco - whitepaper SnmpLink - Links to almost every possible SNMP resource  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
