<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food on shiv.me</title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/food/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food on shiv.me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2016 &amp;copy; Shivanand Velmurugan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.shiv.me/tags/food/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A weekend of culinary delights</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2013/01/14/a-weekend-of-culinary-delights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2013/01/14/a-weekend-of-culinary-delights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The great G.B Shaw, in &amp;ldquo;Man and Superman&amp;rdquo; (not that Superman), quipped, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;There is no love sincerer than the love of food&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;rdquo; I had a weekend, that reminded me how much I love being fed. It also, reminded me of my wayward ways, in keeping the waistline in check, but I diverge. For this Christmas, I got the most amazing gift &amp;ndash; the gift of an evening out trying out food that tasted, as good as it sounds and looks. Without much ado, here is the spread:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gallery ids=&amp;ldquo;13701,13702,13704,13703,13705,13706,13707,13708,13709,13710,13711,13712&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all the hobby chefs for the wonderful delights, and the hospitality. I aspire to such skills in the kitchen, and perhaps I shall be able to pay it forward. Thanks to Christina for the most-awesomest gift ever (yes, we invent words here), and Sophie for &amp;ldquo;subbing&amp;rdquo; for the sick Tina (I owe you one, Sophie!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.socialbites.ca/&#34;&gt;Social Bites&lt;/a&gt; (and you should), get in touch with the wonderful bundle of energy that is Annika! (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SocialBites&#34;&gt;@socialbites&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/socialbites.ca&#34;&gt;Social bites on FB&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the chefs: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wontongirljojo&#34;&gt;@wontongirljojo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jonesboy&#34;&gt;@jonesboy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two-factor authentication and spicy salmon sashimi don</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2012/08/23/two-factor-authentication-and-spicy-salmon-sashimi-don/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2012/08/23/two-factor-authentication-and-spicy-salmon-sashimi-don/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been annoyed. Two or three times a week, I get a flurry of emails from Facebook and twitter claiming that I reset my password. Sounds like a first-world problem? It is. However, I have 4 emails linked to my Facebook account and one to my twitter account. I get on average 15-20 mails a week, and I dutifully dis-avow each one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emptyage.com/post/28679875595/yes-i-was-hacked-hard&#34;&gt;this happens&lt;/a&gt;. It scares the hell out of me, but I procrastinate. After a good two weeks, and 40 mails later, I&amp;rsquo;ve finally caved, and enabled it. Now, it&amp;rsquo;s practically impossible to hack my account. Password + token to access from any new device, and I can remotely revoke access to any device I lose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, what does it have to do with sashimi, you ask? Well, nothing really! That&amp;rsquo;s just the bait to get you to read this most important thing. Don&amp;rsquo;t be like me, and procrastinate forever. Enable two-factor authentication on both &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.google.com/accounts/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=180744&#34;&gt;google&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://m.facebook.com/note.php?note_id=10150172618258920&amp;amp;_rdr&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;! You&amp;rsquo;ll be glad you did. Both have very compelling implementations that are easy to configure and use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security is like good sushi &amp;ndash; once you&amp;rsquo;ve tasted the good kind, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to go back to just good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, here&amp;rsquo;s your reward for reading this far:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/20120823-214038.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/images/20120823-214038.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;20120823-214038.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tandoori spiced fish with cucumber</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/09/25/tandoori-spiced-fish-with-cucumber/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/09/25/tandoori-spiced-fish-with-cucumber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One program&amp;ndash;on Food TV&amp;ndash;that I like to watch, is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gordonramsay.com/corporate/theman/biography/&#34;&gt;Gordon Ramsey&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.channel4.com/food/on-tv/ramsays-kitchen-nightmares/&#34;&gt;Kitchen Nightmares&lt;/a&gt;. He is such a powerful person, who is into what he does for a living. He has inspired me to get of my couch and cook decent food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a recipe from his book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1554700647?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=shvelmurcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1554700647&#34;&gt;Fast Food.&lt;/a&gt; Every guy who wants to cook decent food should have on his shelf. A simple book, with simple recipes that any idiot (aka me) can follow. Most dishes are less than 30 minutes of cooking time.  I&amp;rsquo;m a very imprecise cook, and subtitute freely when I can&amp;rsquo;t find a specific fish or condiment. I have taken the same liberty with this recipe as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/shvelmur/2888542655/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/images/2888542655_603b2e1c08.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_5494&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 skinned Halibut fillets (about 150 gms), or cod, tilapia or turbot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp Hot Madras Curry, or any non-sweet curry paste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tsp superfine sugar (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; cup (150 ml) plain yogurt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cucumbers, peeled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;handful of mint leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lime juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 tbsp of vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heat the oven to 400 F (200 C). Mix the curry paste, olive oil, sugar and all but 2 tbsp of the yogurt. Coat the fish with this mixture and set aside for atleast 20 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cut the cucumber lengthwise (bâtonnet) and toss in the reserved yogurt, chopped mint and the lime juice. You want to be modest with the lime juice. Too much acidity can mask the taste of the fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sear the fillets on an overproof pan&amp;ndash;setting aside the excess marinade&amp;ndash;for about 1.5 minutes on each side or until golden brown. If don&amp;rsquo;t have an overproof pan, just use any skillet and a pre-heated baking pan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spoon over the marinade and place the pan in the oven and cook until done (the insides of the fish turns white and is flaky to cut). Transfer to a warm plate and serve with the cuccumber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, wasn&amp;rsquo;t that simple. Ramsey&amp;rsquo;s a genius in creating simple foods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>