<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shiv.me </title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/jekyll/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2016-02-10 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Battle of the static site generators - part 1</title>
          <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/02/10/battle-of-the-static-site-generators-1/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
          <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2016/02/10/battle-of-the-static-site-generators-1/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I set myself a goal to write more this year - in fact, I attempted to do so once every week. This required me to look at my blog, which led to the inevitable: small changes in what it looked like, led to general dis-satisfcation with the current solution I have to publish my blog, which quickly ballooned into a whole host of activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me step back a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jekyll-is-really-hyde&#34;&gt;Jekyll is really Hyde&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I host my blog on github, using a static site generator - Jekyll. It is written in ruby, has some cool features. Overall, it is a decent solution, but I was never satisfied with options it provided. I have hesistated to hack at it, since ruby isn&amp;rsquo;t my language-du-jour, and most of the changes have been quite minimal. It is also extremely slow&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As any self-respecting programmer is wont to do, instead of writing more posts, and meeting my goal, I delved right into fixing &amp;ldquo;bike-shed&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; in this case, research and use a new static-site generator. Why, you ask? To you, non-existent, ever-questioning inquisitive you, I say &amp;ndash; Why not?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any successful hunt, one &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; make a list: One that shall help determine settle the battle of the generators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must be &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; I mean blazing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Must be in one of the languages I currently hack in: go, nim, c, c++, javascript, python, rust, erlang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should have good defaults &amp;ndash; shouldn&amp;rsquo;t need plugins to perform basic features: syntax highlighting, responsive images, theming,
 permalinks and good markdown support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should have a few good themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good community support and/or documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-contenders&#34;&gt;The contenders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scouring the corners of the internet, I narrowed down on two final choices: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hexo.io/&#34;&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-shiny-shiny&#34;&gt;New shiny, shiny&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They
   - are faster at generating 300+ pages.
   - are opinionated and hence have good defaults.
   - support most of features I am looking for except responsive images.
   - provide extended markdown support by default.
   - hosted by an active community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo-ftw&#34;&gt;Hugo FTW!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Hugo and Hexo are pretty good. They are fast enough for my use, and are implemented in modern languages that I am actively learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo edged out Hexo: It has a few features that look promising and is a bit more fun to hack. It is written in go and this make it ideal. I am switching to Go as a primary language for my hacking needs. A lot of issues, and about 3000 forks is a good opportunity to contribute to a larg-ish project in go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The choice is made. Now to move the herd. I have the daunting task of migrating 300+ posts that were originally posted on different blog engines of the past: blogger, wordpress, and octopress and finally jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In subsequent posts, I will write about a small tool I have built to help with fixing YAML frontmatter after converting posts from html to markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;Slow is relative. I have about 300+ posts, and rendering them into HTML using jekyll, takes a few minutes.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
