<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shiv.me </title>
    <link>/tags/lists/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2010-06-02 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>A list to be on</title>
          <link>/2010/06/a-list-to-be-on/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2010 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
          <guid>/2010/06/a-list-to-be-on/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t explain my silence on this blog, its but an excuse. A lot of things have been happening, both in my personal and professional life, and I&amp;rsquo;m not at liberty to talk about them. Those are for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been writing code - for money, ie - for 9 years now. This obsession started a good 6 years before that. I don&amp;rsquo;t have much to show for it (most of it is copyrighted, or lost across several machines, that weren&amp;rsquo;t mine). One thing that hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed is the burning desire to get near some of my idols &amp;ndash; gods even. When I was 15, I promised myself that I will strive to be at the same level as some of these people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mashable made a &lt;a href=&#34;http://mashable.com/2010/07/04/web-founding-fathers/&#34;&gt;list of people &amp;ndash; fathers of the internet&lt;/a&gt;, and so did &lt;a href=&#34;http://scripting.com/stories/2010/07/04/foundersOfTheWeb.html&#34;&gt;Dave winer&lt;/a&gt;. All of these people have made such great contributions, that it is foolish to not agree with both these lists. However, for me, as a hacker, they interest me less than those who were the developers of software that made the Internet possible. Here is my non-exhaustive list, in no particular order, of the gods I try to emulate, and someday match and surpass (what are we, without lofty goals, eh?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ken Thompson&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rob pike&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stroustroup&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;guido van rossum&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linus torvalds&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dave winer&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jwz&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joshua bloch&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;james gosling&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;miguel de icaza&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And some friends, that are equally important to me as hackers (not the kind that break into your computer)&lt;br /&gt;
- ganesh CS&lt;br /&gt;
- Yuvi panda&lt;br /&gt;
- guru&lt;br /&gt;
- rajasekar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(There are couple who I work with, that should be on that list, but I still have to work with them, and don&amp;rsquo;t want to make anyone jealous. Sorry for leaving you out guys/gals ;) )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a hacker or want to be one, you should look at this list, and pick a few, and engross yourself in their work. That is by far, the best way to get better at what you do. The first step in becoming good, is to find a measuring stick. If anyone from the list is what you measure yourself by, you are bound for greatness. See ya there!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_programmers&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_programmers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace, out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
