<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shiv.me </title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/music-therapy/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2010-03-21 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Some deep shit</title>
          <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/03/21/some-deep-shit/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
          <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/03/21/some-deep-shit/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent conversation about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.melodygardot.com/&#34;&gt;Melody Gardot&lt;/a&gt;, and her &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Melody_Gardot#Discography&#34;&gt;songs&lt;/a&gt;, her &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Melody_Gardot#Accident&#34;&gt;recovery and music therapy&lt;/a&gt; led to the following thoughts. It&amp;rsquo;s some deep shit, but struck me as something that I should share. If you could care less about such things, move along, and forget that this every happened. If not, read on. It might just inspire some more thought&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Person 1: You know I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to believe that each time something hits us hard - there&amp;rsquo;s going to be a lovely gift - only thing you don&amp;rsquo;t see it right away. Takes years sometimes. If only people realise this everyone will want to have problems all the time!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Person 2: What you said is true. But here&amp;rsquo;s something to ponder. If you start believing that everything that hits you hard (or for that matter, everything) results in some unknown good, does it then even hit you as hard?! It is a wonderfully recursive mechanism, where a little bit of trust in life removes a little bit of the need to &amp;ldquo;safeguard&amp;rdquo; oneself, which in turn adds a little bit of trust in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ofcourse, the minute you realize this, the whole recursive chain could unfold, and the transformation can be instantaneous. :) So it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to take years, one just needs to reach a critical level of trust in life or a critical level of understanding that life itself is inconsequential and therefore, the only thing of consequence is how well one can live it &amp;ldquo;in the now&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you think about that? Any comments? thoughts?! Or do you think it is just hippy shit?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m fascinated by the beauty of Miss Gardot&amp;rsquo;s voice, and the strength it took to get it back. Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt of one of her songs, which kept me pre-occupied for a few hours late last night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I gave a thought to fascination I would know it wasn&amp;rsquo;t right to care,&lt;br /&gt;
Logic doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to mind that I am fascinated by the love affair,&lt;br /&gt;
Still my heart would benefit from a little tenderness from time to time, but never mind,&lt;br /&gt;
Cos Baby I&amp;rsquo;m a fool who thinks it&amp;rsquo;s cool to fall in love,&lt;br /&gt;
Baby I should hold on just a moment and be sure it&amp;rsquo;s not for vanity,&lt;br /&gt;
Look me in the eye and tell me love is never based upon insanity,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;from [&lt;em&gt;Baby I&amp;rsquo;m a fool&lt;/em&gt;][3] by [Melody Gardot][3]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/ca/album/baby-im-a-fool/id312917804?i=312917838&#34;&gt;http://itunes.apple.com/ca/album/baby-im-a-fool/id312917804?i=312917838&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
