<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shiv.me </title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/apps/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2010-05-29 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>iCaved</title>
          <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/05/29/icaved/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2010 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
          <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/05/29/icaved/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I did it. I &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/2010/02/03/i-too-have-something-to-say-about-the-ipad.html&#34;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/2010/02/04/ipad-is-ibad-petition.html&#34;&gt;I&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/2010/03/16/so-long-and-thanks-for-the-jailed-iphone.html&#34;&gt;wouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/a&gt;. I said I will hold out for purely &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/2010/02/03/i-too-have-something-to-say-about-the-ipad.html&#34;&gt;ethical reasons&lt;/a&gt;, but it is &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/shiva/status/14946052410&#34;&gt;very hard to resist the iPad&lt;/a&gt;. The first impression in-store is simply &amp;ndash; awesome. This of course is not a surprise and is something that one can expect from apple these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warning: This is a long post ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some thoughts, after a day of use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s fast. Much faster than the iPhone 3GS. This is good news for the upcoming iPhone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The battery lasts a really long time. It was around 80% and I used it for incessantly until it died &lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt; hours later. The a4 processor is at this point THE chip to kill for. If you have any samsung shares, I would dump them now, and load up on apple (although they are a tad &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/finance?q=aapl&#34;&gt;pricy&lt;/a&gt; these days)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone apps are useless and look ugly on the iPad. Don&amp;rsquo;t bother synching any of them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The keyboard is a lot more usable that I thought it would be. I&amp;rsquo;m typing this post at about 60-70% of my usual typing speed. (Only true if inclined at an proper angle &amp;ndash; the perfect angle: the one you get with the iPad case).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I missed the universal back button. I&amp;rsquo;ve been spoiled by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.shiv.me/2010/03/16/so-long-and-thanks-for-the-jailed-iphone.html&#34;&gt;freedom-toting nexus one robot&lt;/a&gt; ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other small annoyances include URL copy pasting between apps, and how the app store lists apps. Exiting the app store every time I install an app is also mind-numbing. I know I can use a Mac and install all apps at one go, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t spend a 1000 dollars for workarounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although I could type very well, creating a blog post is not this device&amp;rsquo;s forte. For one, all the switching back and forth, is a nightmare, and there is simply no way to get the links to apps for instance from the ipad. Adding images is a pain as well (which is why this is a purely text-only post). It is really nice until you want to go beyond its function as a consumption device. Even a little, and it makes you want to get to a mac/pc in a hurry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some apps are just stellar, that make it worthwhile go through the above mentioned niggles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t feel any remorse at having bought it, but at the same time, I&amp;rsquo;m not floored by everything either. That is actually the strength of the device. It is the first time a computing device completely disappears and you interact with data. The experience depends on the app that you are using. Instapaper does a great job, so does the gmail web app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of the drop list widget though. This is the one interface element that gets in the way, and frankly, I&amp;rsquo;m surprised that this got through the apple ui designers. A sliding in from left/right would have been a better option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a little cautious about buying a lot of apps like I did for the iPhone and then quitting the platform although I don&amp;rsquo;t see that happening with the iPad, there is no competition in sight for at least another 18 months, and even then it would take an androId tablet a year to get to this level of refinement (if they ever do)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a still here, here are some must have apps. Most of them are free, so get &amp;lsquo;em now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/instapaper-pro/id288545208?mt=8&#34;&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/goodreader-for-ipad/id363448914?mt=8&#34;&gt;Goodreader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/penultimate/id354098826?mt=8&#34;&gt;Penultimate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/beatwave/id363718254?mt=8&#34;&gt;Beatwave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/tweetdeck-for-ipad/id364153769?mt=8&#34;&gt;Tweetdeck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/epicurious-recipes-shopping/id312101965?mt=8&#34;&gt;Epicurious&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/explore-flickr/id372457895?mt=8&#34;&gt;Exploreflickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/kindle/id302584613?mt=8&#34;&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/nyt-editors-choice/id357066198?mt=8&#34;&gt;Nyt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/alice-for-the-ipad-lite/id364746811?mt=8&#34;&gt;Alice lite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(bonus) put icons for all the google apps you use on the home screen. The web versions are really good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Ok. I&amp;rsquo;ll stop with this) [Dropbox][15]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[15]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/dropbox/id327630330?mt=8&#34;&gt;http://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/dropbox/id327630330?mt=8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
