<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>shiv.me </title>
    <link>/tags/email/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2008-10-15 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>How I handle 1000&#43; emails and 300&#43; blog posts a day</title>
          <link>/2008/10/15/how-i-handle-1000-emails-and-300-blog-posts-a-day/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Shiva Velmurugan</author>
          <guid>/2008/10/15/how-i-handle-1000-emails-and-300-blog-posts-a-day/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Several people are shocked to hear that I read 1000+ emails and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/reader/shared/18301612726860782682&#34;&gt;several hundred blog posts a day&lt;/a&gt;. Ofcourse, when I say that, all I mean is that, I process that much content. I read around 30-40% (That is really the signal-to-noise ratio of web content these days&amp;ndash;and that is, if you are subscribed to high quality feeds)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=&amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;450&amp;rdquo; caption=&amp;ldquo;google reader trends&amp;rdquo;][&lt;img src=&#34;/images/2945049781_d005a9184b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;google reader trends&#34; /&gt;][1][/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of friends was curious how I can handle all that data flow, and I emailed her this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyday, go to bed with a zero count.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use tools to reduce your processing. (use email rules/filters to move mails to manageable folders and Google reader for feeds)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn to skip-read. I use a 2 parse method.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parse through sets of items (email headers or blog post headlines), and mark the ones your need to pay attention to (usually around 40%).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Filter based on short-listed items and then go through them in detail. In the case of blog posts, if something does retain my attention after the first 4 sentences, I skip that item.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(only for blog posts) I mark the ones I have to comment on, and then do my commenting after I finish a folder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you just can&amp;rsquo;t squeeze everything in a day, I either bookmark or mail it to myself to be addressed over the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think? Am I missing something that will make my life a little easier?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Thanks to Aswinanand for pointing this out&amp;ndash;I don&amp;rsquo;t really get 1000+ emails. I was just exaggerating (which is just another way of saying, click-baiting! :) )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/shvelmur/2945049781/&#34;&gt;http://www.flickr.com/photos/shvelmur/2945049781/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
