<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>apple on Rabble-rousing Rambling</title>
    <link>http://blog.shiv.me/tags/apple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in apple on Rabble-rousing Rambling</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2016 &amp;copy; Shivanand Velmurugan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.shiv.me/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to apologize to your users</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2013/07/21/how-to-apologize-to-your-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2013/07/21/how-to-apologize-to-your-users/</guid>
      <description>There has been an increase in security breaches this year. This past week, two services I use were compromised - Tumblr and Apple Developer Connection. Both services informed me of the security breach, and one made me feel like they cared, and the other one didn&amp;rsquo;t. Perhaps I am reading too much into this, but at the very least, it illustrates how important language is, in conveying how much we care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIP Steve Jobs</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/10/05/rip-steve-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/10/05/rip-steve-jobs/</guid>
      <description>DeWitt Clinton once wrote
 What are the hallmarks of a great engineer? A great engineer is characterized by their intelligence, versatility, creativity, loyalty, passion, experience, vision, dedication, composure, humility, and ability.
 Apart from the &amp;ldquo;humility&amp;rdquo; part, which he never cared for, Steve Jobs was the epitome of that description. We shall miss you Mr. Jobs, especially for that keen sense of doing something perfectly.
RIP Steve Jobs, the maker of beautiful things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad and friends</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/05/01/ipad-and-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/05/01/ipad-and-friends/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a year since I sold my kidneys for an iPad. It&amp;rsquo;s been fun. It has replaced every other device I own (ie, a couple of PCs and the nexus one). It&amp;rsquo;s an outright winner, when it comes to reading, especially long-form articles, and books alike. It has become my go-to machine for everyday news, twitter/facebook, and even for browsing my favorite photographers.
It have however remained strictly in the realm of content consumption &amp;ndash; until now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You cribbing bunch of morons</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/04/27/you-cribbing-bunch-of-morons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/04/27/you-cribbing-bunch-of-morons/</guid>
      <description>And now you&amp;rsquo;ve done it!! Bah! I thought it was so cool that I could plot of heat map of my location for a full year. With all the cribbing around the internets about how the iphone is not secure because it stores data (ie a cache of your location data), Apple has decided to squash this wonderful &amp;ldquo;easter egg&amp;rdquo;.
 Sometime in the next few weeks Apple will release a free iOS software update that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No matter what we say</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/03/04/no-matter-what-we-say/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2011/03/04/no-matter-what-we-say/</guid>
      <description>If you weren&amp;rsquo;t in a hole the past few days, you would have heard about the iPad 2 launch. Here&amp;rsquo;s Conan&amp;rsquo;s take on it.
I must say, the cover is a thing of engineering beauty. Kudos on that, Apple, and thanks for screwing over several thousands of your iPad 1 customers, who forked up 9.5 Billion in revenue in 9 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iCaved</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/05/29/icaved/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/05/29/icaved/</guid>
      <description>I did it. I said I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t. I said I will hold out for purely ethical reasons, but it is very hard to resist the iPad. The first impression in-store is simply &amp;ndash; awesome. This of course is not a surprise and is something that one can expect from apple these days.
Warning: This is a long post ..
Here are some thoughts, after a day of use:
 It&amp;rsquo;s fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The day-after the &#34;big&#34; day</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/05/14/the-day-after-the-big-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/05/14/the-day-after-the-big-day/</guid>
      <description>I turned 30 yesterday.
A whole day has passed since I left my 20s. They say it is a big day. They say it is a dreaded day. It was neither. Just busy (which is good).
I chanced upon [Douglas Adams&#39; post][1] from 1999:
&amp;gt; 1. everything that&amp;rsquo;s already in the world when you&amp;rsquo;re born is just normal;
&amp;gt; 2. anything that gets invented between then and before you turn thirty is incredibly exciting and creative and with any luck you can make a career out of it;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So long and thanks for the &#34;jailed&#34; iphone</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/03/16/so-long-and-thanks-for-the-jailed-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/03/16/so-long-and-thanks-for-the-jailed-iphone/</guid>
      <description>[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_737&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignnone&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;] So long oppression[/caption]
Thanks for the iPhone, Mr. Jobs. There is a new way to protest the iPhone. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to sign petitions anymore. I can now take my $500 elsewhere, for a slightly more open experience. I didn&amp;rsquo;t ask for much, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait on your whim any longer (no offense meant to you personally, Mr Jobs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad is iBad petition</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/02/04/ipad-is-ibad-petition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2010/02/04/ipad-is-ibad-petition/</guid>
      <description>http://www.defectivebydesign.org/ipad
If you think that the iPad is promoting DRM of apps that will lead computing in a direction that will undermine the freedom that we currently are enjoying, freedom the seeds of which have been sown over the last few decades, the visit the link above and sign the petition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>\[Jason\] The Case Against Apple--in Five Parts</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2009/08/08/%5Cjason%5C-the-case-against-apple-in-five-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2009/08/08/%5Cjason%5C-the-case-against-apple-in-five-parts/</guid>
      <description>Hi Jason,
I was writing a post very much on the same lines, when I read your mail. I&amp;rsquo;m on my 3rd ipod, 1st iphone and 2nd MBP (one which I ordered just last week). I don&amp;rsquo;t think I can in the right mind buy another iphone or ipod for the amount of control that apple gets.
1. Absolutely. This is a no-brainer, that I&amp;rsquo;m frankly surprised that Steve Jobs does not see?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That queasy feeling</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/01/29/that-queasy-feeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/01/29/that-queasy-feeling/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago, I returned the Ipod touch that I had for exactly 11 days, coz Apple chose to charge me $20. Apart from me being a cheap bas***d, I had this queasy feeling in my gut, about apple products. I felt an unexplainable rage towards Apple, Jobs and the fanboys. I am usually a very moderate person, and it really surprised me that I could harbor such crazy extremism and frustration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPod touch 1.1.1 firmware link</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/01/15/ipod-touch-1.1.1-firmware-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2008/01/15/ipod-touch-1.1.1-firmware-link/</guid>
      <description>Since Apple&amp;rsquo;s is so bent upon disappointing their customers, by introducing paid firmware upgrades, I needed to ensure that I have the option to jail break, my new ipod touch (if need be). (update: the firmware upgrade itself is not paid. Only the newapps are paid). I am going to wait until they release their SDK in February before I jailbreak mine.
I found a link to the 1.1.1 firmware (thanks to Rupert and who-ever posted this).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple iMplant</title>
      <link>http://blog.shiv.me/2005/10/26/apple-implant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.shiv.me/2005/10/26/apple-implant/</guid>
      <description>Have you heard about the latest ipod.
http://www.bbspot.com/News/2005/01/new_ipod_implant.html
http://news.com.com/5208-7354-0.html?forumID=1&amp;amp;threadID=4129&amp;amp;messageID=24004&amp;amp;start=-1
This is amazing.. Imagine being able to have a device implanted in your body, with which you cantrol with your thought, and which will use your brain as a hardrive, and use blood sugar as a battery cell.
Eerie thought envelop me, when I think of what could be?!! Living the matrix ?!!
It is not only the body heat that can be a source of energy (like in &amp;ldquo;The Matrix&amp;rdquo;), even human blood sugar can be harnesed!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
